Witness the beginning of a new dynasty.
Ant-Man and the Wasp: Quantumania is a action, adventure,
science fiction film directed by Peyton Reed.
Super-Hero partners Scott Lang and Hope van Dyne, along with with Hope's parents Janet van Dyne and Hank Pym, and Scott's daughter Cassie Lang, find themselves exploring
the Quantum Realm, interacting with strange new creatures and embarking on an adventure that will push them beyond the limits of what they thought possible.
Scott Lang / Ant-Man, played by Paul Rudd.
Hope Van Dyne / The Wasp, played by Evangeline Lilly.
Dr. Hank Pym, played by Michael Douglas.
Janet Van Dyne, played by Michelle Pfeiffer.
Kang the Conqueror, played by Jonathan Majors.
Cassie Lang, played by Kathryn Newton.
Ant-Man and the Wasp: Quantumania is a 2023 American superhero film based on Marvel
Comics featuring the characters Scott Lang / Ant-Man and Hope Pym / Wasp.
Produced by Marvel Studios and distributed by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures, it is the sequel to Ant-Man
(2015) and Ant-Man and the Wasp (2018), and the 31st film in the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU).
It was directed by Peyton Reed, written by Jeff Loveness, and stars Paul Rudd as Scott Lang and Evangeline Lilly as Hope van Dyne, alongside Jonathan Majors,
Kathryn Newton, David Dastmalchian, Katy O'Brian, William Jackson Harper, Bill Murray, Michelle Pfeiffer, Corey Stoll, and Michael Douglas.
In the film, Scott, Hope, and their family are accidentally transported to the
Quantum Realm and face off against Kang the Conqueror (Majors).
Plans for a third Ant-Man film were confirmed in
November 2019, with Reed and Rudd returning.
Loveness was hired by April 2020, with development
beginning during the COVID-19 pandemic.
The title and new cast members, including the additions of
Majors and Newton, were announced in December 2020.
Filming in Turkey began in early February 2021, and additional
filming occurred in San Francisco in mid-June.
Principal photography began at the end of July at Pinewood
Studios in Buckinghamshire and ended in November.
With a net production budget of $330.1 million, it is one
of the most expensive films ever made.
Ant-Man and the Wasp: Quantumania premiered in Westwood, Los Angeles, on February
6, 2023, and was released in the United States on February 17.
It is the first film, and beginning, of Phase Five of the MCU.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and was a box-office disappointment, grossing $476.1 million
worldwide and becoming one of the few MCU films to not break-even in its theatrical run.
The film explores themes of hero, superhero, ant, stupidity, based on comic.
The tone is thought_provoking.